<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CodeBlue</title><link>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/</link><description>Recent content on CodeBlue</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 20:02:39 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Optimization of a function through genetic algorithm</title><link>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/optimization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 20:02:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/optimization/</guid><description>AIM:
The aim of this project is to write a MATLAB program to optimize the stalagmite function and find the GLOBAL MAXIMA of the function.
STALAGMITE FUNCTION: Stalagmite function is as shown in the figure it is just like any other function. Here we are using the stalagmite function as a function that needs to be optimized to show how we can use MATLAB’s in-built function GA to optimize the stalagmite function.</description></item><item><title>Creating your own OpenFOAM solver</title><link>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/creating_your_own_openfoam_solver/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 19:51:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/creating_your_own_openfoam_solver/</guid><description>AIM:
The aim of this project is to create a custom solver in OpenFOAM that solves a transport equation for a scalar named s.
OBJECTIVES:
The solver must be modified from icoFoam which is present in $FOAM/applications/solvers/incompressible/icoFoam. The case should be a scalar quantity &amp;rsquo;s&amp;rsquo; that is being transported by velocity u and the transport equation is represented by {del u }/{del t } + nabla. (us) = 0 The case must be modified from $FOAM_TUTORIALS/incompressible/icoFoam/cavity.</description></item><item><title>CFD meshing of a Tesla Cyber truck</title><link>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/cfd_meshing_of_a_tesla_cyber_truck/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 19:32:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/cfd_meshing_of_a_tesla_cyber_truck/</guid><description>AIM:
The aim of this project is to pre-process the tesla cyber truck and mesh it. The CAD model of which can be found here.
OBJECTIVES:
For the given model, check and solve all geometrical errors and Assign appropriate PIDs. Perform meshing with the suitable Target length and element Quality criteria.
PROCEDURE:
We start with importing the file.
The geometry is filled with single cons to eliminate these we use the Topo option.</description></item><item><title>Flow over ahmed body</title><link>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/flow_over_ahmed_body/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 16:08:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/flow_over_ahmed_body/</guid><description>AIM:
This project aims to simulate the flow over Ahmed body in Ansys Fluent.
OBJECTIVES OF THE PROJECT:
*Generate Velocity and pressure contours.
*Calculate the drag coefficient plot for a refined case.
*Generate the vector plot clearly showing the wake region. *Perform the grid independency test and evaluate the values of drag and lift with each case. THEORY
What is an Ahmed body?
The Ahmed body is a geometric shape first proposed by S.</description></item><item><title>FSAE Car Project</title><link>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/fsae_car/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 15:12:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/fsae_car/</guid><description>AIM:
The aim of this project is to simulate the flow around an FSAE car in converge.
OBJECTIVES OF THE PROJECT:
*Clean up the geometry. *Flag the parts as separate boundaries.
*Create a virtual wind tunnel.
*Run the simulation for two different types of Races.
Race-1 Racing track conditions - Lot of turns
Average lap speeds - 45kmph 70% turns at 45 degrees
20% turns at 80 degrees
10% turns at 20 degrees</description></item><item><title>1D Supersonic Nozzle flow simulation using MacCormac Method</title><link>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/secondposts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 10:52:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/secondposts/</guid><description>AIM:
Aim of this project is to simulate Isentropic flow through a quasi 1D subsonic-supersonic nozzle.
OBJECTIVES :
The objectives of this project are
To solve the equations that govern the flow through a supersonic nozzle for both conservative and non conservative forms.
To find the differences between them by comparing their solutions.
Steady-state distribution of primitive variables inside the nozzle. Time-wise variation of the primitive variables.
Variation of Mass flow rate distribution inside the nozzle at different time steps during the time-marching process.</description></item><item><title>Parsing NASA thermodynamic data using MATLAB</title><link>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/first_post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 12:24:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://satyasasank.github.io/CodeBlue/posts/first_post/</guid><description>AIM:
The aim of this project is to write a MATLAB program that can read a file that contains thermodynamic data in a polynomial format (eg. files from CHEMKIN II).
NASA thermodynamic data
OBJECTIVES OF THE PROJECT:
The above file contains a set of compounds for which a set of coefficients are given. These coefficients are used in the above equation to get the values for Cp, enthalpy, and entropy. Each compound or gas contains 14 coefficient and the first 7 coefficients are to be used if the temperature are high and the next 7 coefficients are to be used if the temperatures are low.</description></item></channel></rss>